<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>Boring papers from arXiv</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">The Bad Papers on ML, AI and Statistics</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2017-11-30T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Statistics -- Machine Learning</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/1711.11293"/></rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image><item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/1711.11293">
<title>Parallel-Data-Free Voice Conversion Using Cycle-Consistent Adversarial Networks. (arXiv:1711.11293v1 [stat.ML])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/1711.11293</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We propose a parallel-data-free voice conversion (VC) method that can learn a
mapping from source to target speech without relying on parallel data. The
proposed method is general-purpose, high quality, and parallel-data-free, which
works without any extra data, modules, or alignment procedure. It is also
noteworthy that it avoids over-smoothing, which occurs in many conventional
statistical model-based VC methods. Our method uses a cycle-consistent
adversarial network (CycleGAN) with gated convolutional neural networks (CNNs)
and an identity-mapping loss. The CycleGAN learns forward and inverse mappings
simultaneously using adversarial and cycle-consistency losses. This makes it
possible to find an optimal pseudo pair from unpaired data. Furthermore, the
adversarial loss contributes to reducing over-smoothing of the converted
feature sequence. We configure a CycleGAN with gated CNNs and train it with an
identity-mapping loss. This allows the mapping function to capture sequential
and hierarchical structures while preserving linguistic information. We
evaluated our method on a parallel-data-free VC task. An objective evaluation
showed that the converted feature sequence was near natural in terms of global
variance and modulation spectra. A subjective evaluation showed that the
quality of the converted speech was comparable to that obtained with the
GMM-based method under advantageous conditions with parallel data.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Kaneko_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takuhiro Kaneko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Kameoka_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hirokazu Kameoka&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item></rdf:RDF>